Guide to the Campus Ministry Women Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
Campus Ministry Women records
1969-1996
RG 68
Yale University Divinity School Library
1.5
(3 boxes)
The collection traces the operations of the Campus Ministry Women organization from its founding in 1974 until its disbanding in 1996.
Campus Ministry Women
Historical Note
The Women in Campus Ministry organization was founded in 1974 and changed its name to Campus Ministry Women in 1975. Campus Ministry Women was a national organization of Catholic, Protestant, and Jewish women who were involved in ministry in higher education. It provided a communications network, sponsored conferences and educational experiences, and served as a support and advocacy organization. The organization disbanded in 1996.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Scope and Contents
Legal documents, minutes, financial records, programmatic material, correspondence, and newsletters document the formation and work of Campus Ministry Women.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series:
I. Administrative Records
II. Correspondence
III. Newsletters
Universities and colleges -- Religion; Campus Ministry Women (Organization); Campus Ministry Women
- Administrative Records, 1974-1995; Series I
  - Articles of Incorporation and Amendments, 1975-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - By-laws, Mission statements, brochures, 1979, no date (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Documents related to tax exempt status, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Steering Committee minutes, 1988, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes and notes, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Membership and dues, 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  - Conference: Campus Ministry Women in the West, 1976-03 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Conferences, 1980, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Conference: "From the Womb of the Morning", 1988-07 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Conference: "Living with Otherness", 1989-07 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Conferences, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Financial records, 1970-1995 (Box 1, Folder 14-18)
- Correspondence and Communications, 1969-1996; Series II
  - Letters, proposals, memos, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Statements, letters, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Including Lilly Grant proposal, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Including regarding Danforth Consultation, 1975 January - April (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Including regarding Boulder Conference, 1975 May - September (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Letters, report on CMW Coordinators' meeting, 1975 October - December (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Letters, notes, reports, 1976 January - June (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Letters, notes, reports, 1976 July - December (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Letters, reflections, 1977 January - July (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Including regarding the National Meeting of Women Theologizing for Action, 1977 August - December (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Letters, memos, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Letters, flyer, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Letters, evaluation summary, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Letters, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Letters, press release, notes, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Letters, report, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Letters, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Including regarding disbanding the organization, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Newsletters, 1970-1995; Series III
  - Notes and newsletters compiled by Marna McKenzie, 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Women's Campus Ministry Caucus Newsletter - Volume 1, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Women's Campus Ministry Caucus Newsletter - Volume 2, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Women's Campus Ministry Caucus Newsletter - Volume 3 and The Interim, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - The Interim and first issue of Campus Ministry Women Newsletter, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Campus Ministry Women Newsletter, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Campus Ministry Women Newsletter, 1980, 1981, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Campus Ministry Women Newsletter, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Campus Ministry Women Newsletter, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Campus Ministry Women Newsletter, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Campus Ministry Women Newsletter, 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 47)